[Music]
[音乐]
okay as mentioned my name is Paul Harris
好的，如上所述，我叫Paul Harris
I'm the lead developer on Cloud Foundry
我是Cloud Foundry的首席开发人员
Java client not as was tweeted earlier
Java客户端不像以前那样发推文
the whole of Cloud Foundry that would be
整个Cloud Foundry将会是
a bit generous so what is this talk it's
有点大方，这是什么话题
an introduction to reactive programming
反应式编程简介
now I want to stress that from the start
现在我想从一开始就强调
this is an introduction so if you're
这是一个介绍，所以如果你是
already pretty up on reactive and you
已经相当活跃了，你
know how it works and your bat flops and
知道它是如何工作的以及蝙蝠拖鞋和
mono and all the rest of it then you
单声道和所有其余的然后你
don't have to stay it's okay to walk
不必停留，可以步行
we're going to have some background
我们将有一些背景
about where reactive comes from that's
关于反应是从哪里来的
going to be pretty short and after this
会很短，之后
morning's keynote it's going to be even
早上的主题演讲将会变得平淡
shorter we're going to look at a
简短一点，我们来看一下
practical example coded live and I've
实际示例编码现场，我已经
just realized I've never coded standing
只是意识到我从未编码过
up before so that'll be interesting and
之前，这样会很有趣，
just to stress again this is for your
再次强调这是给你的
benefit so if this is too simple for you
受益，所以如果这对您来说太简单
please leave if it's too complicated for
如果太复杂，请离开
you I guess please please and leave and
你我想请你离开
see me later
待会见
so why am i presenting this I've been
所以我为什么要介绍这个我一直
using project reactor the rebooted
使用项目反应器重新启动
version that was mentioned earlier for
之前提到的版本
about three years over three years maybe
三年大概三年
we started on the Cloud Foundry Java
我们从Cloud Foundry Java开始
client at the same time pretty much as
客户几乎同时
spring boot with spring sorry project
Spring Boot与Spring对不起项目
reactor was being rebooted which means
反应堆正在重新启动，这意味着
we were its first customer we had a huge
我们是它的第一个客户，我们有很多
input I think into how it worked out the
我认为它是如何工作的
various real-world decisions that were
各种现实世界的决定
made which I think made it better and
我认为更好的
certainly made the Java client much
当然使Java客户
better because I started three years ago
更好，因为我三年前开始
I didn't have any background in reactive
我没有任何反应式背景
it wasn't you know that much of a thing
你不是很了解
back then so I would guess I have made
那时我想我已经做了
all of the mistakes it is possible to
所有的错误都有可能
make my programming reactively and I may
反应性地进行编程，我可能
well show a few of them to you today
今天向您展示其中的一些
final thing to say is that I'm a normal
最后要说的是我很正常
developer you've heard a lot about the
开发人员，您已经听说过很多有关
rockstars I'm just like you guys I
摇滚明星我就像你们我一样
picked up this thing because I needed to
拿起这个东西，因为我需要
pick it up for work and here's some of
拿起它来工作，这里有一些
what I've learned so to clarify I'm not
我学到的东西，以澄清我不是
a Java ninja and not a java wizard and
Java忍者而不是Java向导
not to drive a Jedi or a
不要开车绝地或
Java blue the bear for that matter I am
Java Blue为此我承担了责任
none of these things just just one of
这些东西都不是其中之一
you okay so this all started out in 2013
你好，所以这一切始于2013年
with the reactive manifesto which was an
与反应性宣言，这是一个
attempt to codify some of the thinking
试图整理一些思想
that was going on at the time about how
当时的情况如何
modern applications should behave
现代应用程序应表现
the manifesto came up with four main
宣言提出了四个主要建议
ideas four concepts applications should
想法四个概念的应用应该
be responsive so that doesn't mean that
反应灵敏，这并不意味着
they should be as quick as they possibly
他们应该尽可能快
can be but they should always feel like
可以，但是他们应该总是觉得
they are making progress so if you have
他们正在进步，所以如果你有
to trade off a little speed for a little
牺牲一点速度
bit of feedback or you know something
一些反馈，或者您知道一些
else like that then that's okay it
那样的话就可以了
should be resilient so if you have an
应该有弹性，所以如果你有一个
error in a particular part of your
您特定部分的错误
application or an application with a
应用程序或具有
larger system that shouldn't take the
较大的系统，不应采用
whole thing down you should be able to
整个事情你应该能够
cope with that as best you can
尽力而为
it should be elastic which is I've
它应该是弹性的
always thought of that as being kind of
总是认为这是一种
scalability really but if there's more
确实具有可扩展性，但如果还有更多
to it than that it's about making the
而不是关于
best use of the resources you have
充分利用您拥有的资源
available so the one of the keynotes
可用，因此主题演讲之一
this morning Ben was talking about the
今天早上，本在谈论
having multiple threads running and
运行多个线程并
being able to with existing models you
能够使用现有模型
tend to be CPU bound because you've got
往往受CPU限制，因为
all these threads all this memory or
所有这些线程所有这些内存或
this contention going on and you're not
这种争论还在继续，而你不是
actually using the CPU that you've got
实际使用您拥有的CPU
available to you so elastic is about
可以让您有弹性
making better use of things like that
更好地利用诸如此类的东西
fooling various connections all this
愚弄各种联系
sort of stuff and finally it should be
东西，最后应该是
message driven rather than event-driven
消息驱动而不是事件驱动
so manifestos are great but they don't
所以宣言很棒，但他们却没有
compile I've got a message up here tell
编译我这里有一条消息告诉
me I've got 11 minutes of speaking time
我我有11分钟的发言时间
left which is a little concerning but
离开这有点令人担忧，但
I'll try and go faster than that and so
我会努力做到的更快
the next step in this adventure was
这次冒险的下一步是
reactive streams which defined a set of
反应性流定义了一组
interfaces for how we might deal with
我们可能如何处理的接口
reactive streaming situations they
他们在反应式流媒体情况下
defined four main interfaces you have a
定义了四个主要界面
publisher which is something that emits
发布者发出的东西
things
东西
that could normally be data so it can be
通常可以是数据，因此可以是
strings or whatever it might be but also
字符串或其他内容
you can be emitting signals to say this
你可能会发出信号说这个
this signal is complete or whatever it
这个信号是完整的
might be you have a subscriber that's
可能是您有一个订阅者
the thing that listens to the signals
听信号的东西
that are coming in if you put those two
如果你把那两个放进去
together then you have a subscription so
在一起，那么您有一个订阅，所以
a publisher communicating with a
发布者与
subscriber is a subscription the key
订阅者是订阅的关键
point to make there is that a publisher
指向有一个发布者
is setting up the potential to publish
正在建立发布的潜力
information but until you get a
信息，但是直到您获得
subscriber attached to it then it's not
订户附加到它不是
necessarily publishing that information
必须发布该信息
well the way we generally work with
我们通常的合作方式
imperative code is you write a program
命令性代码是您编写程序
you run it and it starts doing stuff and
您运行它，它开始做事，
generally speaking with reactive
一般而言，反应性
programs it just gets ready to do stuff
程序就可以开始做事了
and wait for this signal that it should
并等待该信号，它应该
actually consume the results and the
实际消耗结果，
final type that they defined was a
他们定义的最终类型是
processor which is a combination of a
处理器是一个
publisher and a subscriber that allows
发布者和允许
you to process data okay that's the the
您可以处理数据了
basic interface definitions but the
基本的接口定义，但
intention was from reactive streams that
意图来自反应性流
that would move on to a more useful real
那会变成一个更有用的真实
world implementations of that basic
基本的世界实现
specification and one of those is
规范，其中之一是
project reactor so it's turning reactive
项目反应堆，所以它变成了反应堆
streams into a framework you can
流入一个框架，您可以
actually use and there has all sorts of
实际使用，并且有各种各样的
convenience methods in there that will
那里的便利方法
be helpful to you I took a look back the
对你有帮助，我回头看看
first commit was in 10th of November
第一次提交是在11月10日
2015 I mentioned that to illustrate that
2015年我提到那是为了说明
this is a major project that's been
这是一个重大的项目
going on for three and a half years now
持续了三年半
for an obvious Matt so this is not a
显然是马特，所以这不是
casual undertaking it's something this
随便的事情就是这样
brings taken very seriously and I think
带来非常重视，我认为
that's reflected in the quality of the
这反映在
reactive frameworks that are now
现在的反应性框架
available to you through spring there
在春天到你那里
are many elements a couple of new ones
有很多新元素
one I hadn't even heard of before we
我之前从未听说过的一个
mentioned in the keynote this morning
今天上午在主题演讲中提到
but probably the the three big ones a
但可能是三大
main interest is reactor core so that's
主要兴趣是反应堆堆芯，所以
the the basic provision reactor nettie
基本供应反应堆网络
which is the implementation of
这是执行
Nathu suited to project reactor that if
纳图适合于项目反应堆，如果
you're coming from the web MVC world
您来自网络MVC世界
that replaces Tomcat as the server
将Tomcat替换为服务器
container and the final one is react
容器，最后一个是反应
test which is a bunch of really good
测试这是一堆真的很好
useful methods for and testing reactive
用于测试反应的有用方法
streams which is a tricky thing
流是一件棘手的事情
sometimes so before we get into the code
有时是这样，在我们进入代码之前
there's a couple of key concepts to
有几个关键概念
understand we I mentioned earlier about
了解我们之前提到的内容
publishers which is this reactive
出版商对此有何反应
streams idea and in project reactor they
流的想法，并在项目反应堆中
decided to have two specialized
决定有两个专业
publishers so you have a sort of a
发布商，所以您有一种
general one which is a flux and we've
一般的，这是一种变化，我们已经
seen those mentioned already today as
看到今天已经提到的那些
well and the flux is essentially the
好，通量本质上是
same as a publisher with many methods
与发布者一样，有很多方法
added on and so forth it will emit 0 to
加等等，它将发出0到
n elements it's unbounded so it will
n个元素是无界的，所以它将
potentially keep emitting until the heat
可能一直散发直到发热量
death of the universe I guess or until
我猜是直到宇宙的死亡
it for an active data that needs to emit
它用于需要发出的活动数据
there's this more specialized type which
有这种更专业的类型
is a mono which is a publisher of 0 or 1
是单声道，它是0或1的发布者
elements so the reason this was done was
元素，所以这样做的原因是
mainly as a sort of a real-world
主要是作为一种现实世界
decision that not everything is a flux
决定不是一切都是通量
you know sometimes that you're making a
你知道有时候你在做一个
call and you're expecting to get back a
打电话给您，您期望得到一个
single value or potentially no value at
单值或可能无值
all so for code optimizations and for
所有这些对于代码优化和
being able to work in the real world
能够在现实世界中工作
with this tool it can be handy to narrow
使用此工具可以很容易地缩小
things down and say here's a mono so
事情下来，说这是一个单声道
here's are the methods that are specific
这是特定的方法
to this particular thing and I found
对这件事，我发现
using it that it also helps me to get
使用它也可以帮助我获得
into the my right mindset that if I know
进入我正确的心态，如果我知道
I'm dealing with Manos then then I'm
我要和马诺斯打交道，然后我
thinking in that way of ok I need to
以这种方式思考，我需要
think about one value coming back and I
考虑一个价值回来，我
need to handle the fact if nothing comes
如果什么都没有需要处理这个事实
back and that's a separate case so it's
返回，这是一个单独的案例，所以
an both room code and from a
房间代码和
philosophical perspective I guess it's a
哲学的角度，我想这是一个
quite a useful distinction so we're
很有用的区别，所以我们
going to look at both of those in a
要看一看这两个
moment
时刻
so here is our simple application we're
所以这是我们的简单应用程序
going to use for the demo try and make
将用于演示尝试
that much bigger so it's a spring boot
更大，所以是 spring boot
application as you can see it doesn't
您可以看到它没有
particularly have to be it's just a
特别是它只是一个
convenience I'm sure I don't need to
方便，我确定我不需要
sell all you folks about the the
卖给你们所有关于
benefits of using spring boot I have a
使用 spring boot 的好处我有一个
repository of employees I'm using JPA
我正在使用JPA的员工资源库
repository I can see if I have to do
我可以查看是否需要做的存储库
this again I'm already gonna have to
再次，我已经必须
convert that to spring data or to DBC we
将其转换为spring数据或DBC
have an object of employee very simple
有一个很简单的员工对象
just named pension ID and role you can
只需命名退休金ID和角色即可
see I've used the app data annotation
看到我已经使用了应用程序数据注释
there that's a Lombok thing just to save
那只是为了保存龙目岛的东西
me having to generate getters and
我必须产生吸气剂和
setters and so on again not required for
二传手等等，对于
this so that's all the details around it
这就是周围的所有细节
and now for the actual code so we have a
现在是实际的代码，所以我们有一个
rest controller just like that and we
像这样的 rest controller ，我们
have a number of functions in here now I
我现在在这里有很多功能
should point out this is a demo app it's
应该指出，这是一个演示应用程序
not terribly well structured I just
我的结构不是很好
wanted to get everything into one class
想把所有的东西都归为一类
so if that's making you feel sad then
所以如果这让你感到难过
just think of it as legacy code and
只是将其视为旧版代码，
we'll fix it later we have another
我们稍后再修复
number of functions in here we can do a
在这里我们可以做一些功能
mapping of to employees where we say
映射到我们所说的员工
give me all of the employees and it just
给我所有的员工，它只是
spits out a list we can search for an
吐出一个列表，我们可以搜索
individual employee and give it an ID we
个人雇员，并给我们一个ID，我们
get back an employee or a message saying
找回员工或留言说
that that employee couldn't be found we
找不到那个员工，我们
can search for problem records where we
可以在我们那里查找问题记录
go through and look at all of the
经历一下所有的
employees and the database and decide if
员工和数据库，并决定是否
there's something wrong with their day
他们的日子有些问题
to say they've got a missing data entry
说他们缺少数据输入
or spelling mistake or something like
或拼写错误或类似的内容
that we can create a new employee this
我们可以创建一个新员工
is interesting because we have this
很有趣，因为我们有这个
pension lookup that will call out to a
退休金查询
service and give us a pension ID
服务并给我们退休金ID
based on that person's name so we've got
根据那个人的名字，所以我们
a little bit of communication there and
那里有一点交流
finally we have scuse me
终于我们骂我了
update pension records so rather than
更新退休金记录，而不是更新
where with the new employee we go and
我们与新员工一起去哪里
get a specific record for that employee
获得该员工的特定记录
we can update all of the employees
我们可以更新所有员工
pension records so we call out multiple
退休金记录，所以我们调出多个
times to this service to get the IDS
该服务获取IDS的时间
that we need and then down at the bottom
我们需要的，然后在底部
we've got a couple of convenience
我们有一些方便
methods so we need to take this
方法，所以我们需要采取这个
imperative code and make it something
命令性代码并使其有所作为
that's reactive and step one because
这是反应性的，是第一步，因为
we're at a spring conference is we open
我们正在春季会议上
our pump and at the moment we're using
我们的泵，现在我们正在使用
web MVC to both ride all that get
Web MVC都可以发挥所有作用
mapping and goodness and all the rest
映射和善良，其余所有
we're going to get rid of that and we're
我们将摆脱它，我们
going to add a dependency to spring boot
将为Spring Boot添加依赖项
start to web flux so whereas before you
开始上网，所以在您之前
are all used to having a web MVC we're
都习惯了使用Web MVC
now using web blocks which is
现在使用的Web块
essentially the same thing clearly there
那里基本上是同一件事
will be differences because it's dealing
将有所不同，因为它正在处理
in a different term a different model of
用不同的术语来说，
programming if you like but it is the
编程，如果你喜欢，但这是
the non-blocking asynchronous the
非阻塞异步
reactive approach to doing whatever the
反应性的方法来做任何事情
web MVC does something that I've seen
Web MVC做一些我所见过的事情
highlighted a couple of times is to
强调了几次是为了
point out that web hooks doesn't replace
指出网络挂钩不会取代
web MVC where BAM they see is not going
他们看到的BAM不在的Web MVC
anywhere
任何地方
this is just if you're doing a reactive
这就像你在做反应式
style then this is the thing that you
风格然后这就是你的事
should be using so we've changed some
应该使用，所以我们已经改变了一些
dependencies we'll start running
依赖关系，我们将开始运行
and if we take a look at the console we
如果我们看一下控制台，
can see down here that we've started
可以在这里看到我们已经开始
nettie on port 8081 BV ously it would
nettie端口8081 BV上会
have been running on Tomcat and if we go
已经在Tomcat上运行，如果我们去
over to my little test suite I can run
转到我可以运行的小测试套件
the various queries that we were earning
我们所获得的各种查询
that we have available to us and we can
我们有空，我们可以
see the data comes back from from them
看到数据从他们那里回来
all so I can get users I can create
所有这些都可以吸引我可以创建的用户
myself as a user and I get back my
自己作为用户，我回来了
pension ID that's great I can search for
我可以搜索的退休金ID非常好
problems and I'll get a list of all the
问题，我会得到所有
users who've got issues with them like a
遇到问题的用户就像
missing role for example I can do a
缺少角色，例如我可以做一个
search for a user that I know exists and
搜索我知道存在的用户，然后
I get back that the users details I can
我回想起我可以提供的用户详细信息
search for user that doesn't exist and I
搜索不存在的用户，我
get back a 404 because that user wasn't
找回404，因为该用户不是
found and finally I can do a pension
找到了，最后我可以养老
clean which connects to a slow
清洁连接慢
connection I know it's slow because I
连接我知道它很慢，因为我
put thread sleeps in there and I get
把线程睡在那里，我得到
back ok
还可以
I get back the results showing me the
我得到的结果显示给我
updated pension information and if I
更新了养老金信息，如果我
take a look over here I'd got a Asus out
看一下这里，华硕出来了
in there that tells me what thread I was
在那里告诉我我当时是哪个线程
using so I was using one fret and one
使用，所以我正在使用一个品格和一个
thread for all of the calls I did to
我做过的所有通话的线程
this low service nonetheless I am now
如此低的服务我现在
running on Nettie I've enabled web flux
在Nettie上运行我已启用网络流量
so I guess that means that we're now
所以我想这意味着我们现在
reactive and we can all finish not quite
反应性的，我们都不能完全完成
it is impressive to me though that
尽管那对我印象深刻
although this is quite a simple
虽然这很简单
application we didn't have to change
我们不需要更改的应用程序
anything all of that still runs because
所有这一切仍然运行，因为
all of the functionality that we're
我们所拥有的所有功能
already using I'll find the class though
已经在使用，我会找到课程
all the functionality that we're using
我们正在使用的所有功能
still exists so it's not necessarily a
仍然存在，所以不一定
huge explosion if you decide to move
如果您决定移动，将会发生巨大的爆炸
over you can start doing it a little bit
结束，你可以开始做一点
it's time
是时候了
does depend on if you've been using
取决于您是否一直在使用
Tomcat specific or particular servlet
Tomcat特定或特定的servlet
features obviously but in general it
功能明显，但总的来说
tries to make the transition as easy as
试图使转换尽可能容易
possible having said that we do actually
可能说我们实际上在做
need to start using things like flux and
需要开始使用助焊剂和
mono to find out what we do next so
单声道，以找出下一步要做的事情
we'll start off with the simplest query
我们将从最简单的查询开始
that we've got which is just to list all
我们所拥有的只是列出所有
employees and the moments it's got a
员工和当下的时刻
list of employee and we just called the
员工列表，我们刚刚将其称为
repository and it just dumps everything
仓库，它只是转储一切
back to us in the form of a list and
以列表的形式返回给我们，
then web MVC converts that into
然后，Web MVC会将其转换为
something that we can display on a web
我们可以在网络上显示的内容
page or in my rest client so the first
页面或我的其他客户端中的第一个
thing we need to do is say well we're
我们需要做的就是说我们
not dealing with lists anymore we're
不再处理列表了
dealing with flux and immediately that
处理通量，立即
gives us an error because this return
给我们一个错误，因为这个回报
repository findall is still doing things
仓库findall还在做事
with a list so we need to work out some
有一个清单，所以我们需要制定一些
way of converting that into a flux
将其转换为通量的方式
handily something that's not
方便地不是
particularly in the reactive stream
特别是在反应流中
respect because it's that's a very high
尊重，因为那是非常高的
level document but is added in project
级别文档，但已添加到项目中
reactor an example of one of the things
反应堆的一个例子之一
that it will give you for free we have a
它将免费为您提供，我们有一个
method that we can call to do that so we
我们可以调用以执行此操作的方法
start with a flux and we choose from
从助焊剂开始，我们从中选择
iterable and because repository final
迭代且因为存储库是最终的
find all returns less that's an interval
找出所有返回值少于一个间隔
nice and easy so we can put that in
很好很容易，所以我们可以把它放在
there
那里
get rid of that make sure we're
摆脱这一点，确保我们
returning it now when I restart I should
现在，当我重启时返回它应该
explain I've been working in go for the
解释我一直在为
last few months so if I miss out some
最近几个月，所以如果我错过了一些
semicolons don't judge me too harshly
分号不要对我太苛刻
clearly there should be a semicolon in
显然在里面应该有一个分号
there just do it for me if I then might
如果可以的话，就为我做
get recall again get caught then I get
再次得到回忆，然后被抓住
the same list that I had before so those
与我之前的清单相同
of you who are thinking back on what I
你们在回想我
was saying earlier will have noticed
之前说过会注意到
that we've got a publisher but it
我们有一个出版商，但是
doesn't appear based on the code that we
不会根据我们的代码出现
have a subscriber in much the same way
拥有订阅者的方式大致相同
that web MVC takes this basic gap
Web MVC弥补了这一基本差距
mapping and turns it into something that
映射并将其转换为
we can provide to a web page or to the
我们可以提供给网页或
cocoa client the web phlox is doing the
可可客户网络福禄考正在
same thing it is the subscriber so
同样是订户，所以
whenever it receives a call it initiates
每当收到呼叫时，它都会启动
that subscription and says give me the
该订阅并说给我
data that you got for this endpoint
您为此端点获得的数据
that's fantastic because keeping control
太好了，因为保持控制
of subscribers can get a little
的订户可以得到一点
complicated and that's one of the things
复杂，这就是其中之一
you can look forward to in your future
你可以期待你的未来
if you using reactive project react to
如果您使用反应式项目做出反应
makes it as easy as it can but there are
使它尽可能容易，但是有
still some tricks around knowing what
关于知道什么仍然有些技巧
thread you're on I'm making sure that
线程你在我确保
you've closed down things okay so we've
你已经关闭了一切，所以我们
done that and I have notes as well let
做到了，我也有笔记
me just make sure I've not forgotten
我只是确保我没有忘记
anything on there so we started that by
那里的任何东西，所以我们开始
beginning our entire flow as short as it
尽可能短地开始我们的整个流程
was with the flux now we're gonna look
有了助焊剂，现在我们要看
at a similar case but we're gonna start
在类似的情况下，但我们要开始
with a mono instead so we're gonna look
用单声道代替，所以我们要看
at the find and employee by ID in a
在查找和员工中按ID
moment you can see finds by ID throws an
您看到ID的查找信息的那一刻就会抛出一个
exception if there's a problem I had a
如果有问题，我会例外
404 so we might want to do something
404，所以我们可能想做点什么
similar to what we had before and we
和以前一样
could try something like this we say
可以尝试这样的事情，我们说
mono just so I just want you to give me
单声道，所以我只想让你给我
a mono and I want you
一个单声道，我想要你
create that mono from posit REE I'm
我从posit REE创建那个单声道
gonna give it an ID
要给它一个ID
but it's a problem with that and the
但这是一个问题
problem is that find BIID refer to
问题是找到BIID指的是
returns an optional because it doesn't
返回一个可选的，因为它不
know if it's going to find anything or
知道是否会找到任何东西或
not and handily we have a method that
不方便地我们有一种方法
will handle that situation which is just
将处理那种情况
or empty and what that says is return
或为空，表示返回
the mono that you get back from whatever
你从任何东西回来的单声道
call this is but if you don't get
叫这是，但是如果你不明白
anything back then just return an empty
什么都回来然后就返回一个空
so the key thing here is that we're
所以这里的关键是
always dealing with Manos so we need
总是和马诺斯打交道，所以我们需要
Manos to be passed around but so if we
Manos将被传递，但是如果我们
don't get something back we don't want
不要拿回我们不想要的东西
to have an error from it particularly we
从中有一个错误，特别是我们
just want to say here's what I got back
只想说这是我回来的
which was nothing in a mono form and you
那不是单声道形式的，而你
can carry on
可以继续
we still also need to have this
我们还需要这个
exception and we can do that in a
例外，我们可以在
slightly different way to the imperative
强制命令的方式略有不同
style by saying okay we know we might
说好就知道我们可能会
get back a value and that's fine we can
找回价值，我们可以
just pass on but if we don't get
只是继续下去，但如果我们不明白
something back then we want to switch
回到我们想切换的地方
what we're providing by providing a new
我们通过提供一个新的
mono that we can use and we are going to
我们可以使用的单声道，我们将
do
做
and I've done something terribly wrong
我做错了什么
so I should look at my notes to make
所以我应该看看我的笔记
sure I can fix it yeah
我肯定可以解决这个问题
when I said that I have made most of the
当我说我已经充分利用了
mistakes that you can make him using
你可以让他使用的错误
reactor one of the first mistakes I
反应堆我的第一个错误之一
think I made was to forget that we're
以为我所做的就是忘记我们
not returning an employee anymore we're
再也不回员工了
returning a mono of an employee so we
返回一个员工的单声道，所以我们
now have the same functionality that we
现在具有与我们相同的功能
had before but instead of throwing an
曾经有过，但没有扔一个
exception we are returning either the
例外，我们返回了
value that we got or we are passing on a
我们获得或正在传递的价值
mono of an exception this is an
单声道的例外，这是一个
important thing about project reactor
关于项目反应堆的重要事情
and reactive programming that errors are
和反应式编程，错误是
values just the same as a string or an
值与字符串或
employee or anything else as part of
员工或其他任何一部分
that resilience we mentioned earlier you
我们之前提到的韧性
don't necessarily want to panic just
不一定要惊慌
because you've found an error you want
因为您发现了想要的错误
to pass that on to somebody perhaps
传递给某人
several chains down the line that has
几个连锁店
the ability to deal with that error in a
处理一个错误的能力
sensible way so for us here we're just
明智的方式，所以对于我们来说，我们只是
going to say I've got this error and you
会说我有这个错误，你
should do with it what you want so if I
应该用它来做你想要的，如果我
run that
运行那个
and this is doing a search for a user so
这是在搜索用户，所以
here's a user that exists and that's
这是一个存在的用户，那就是
fine his user that doesn't exist so I
罚款不存在的用户，所以我
created this mano of an error and passed
创建这个错误的mano并通过
it on and I've passed it on to Webb flux
它已经传递到Webb助焊剂上
which is the thing that's doing the
这是在做的事情
SUBSCRIBE and it's decided that when it
订阅，并决定何时
sees errors like that it will pass them
看到这样的错误，它将通过它们
on to the users as a 404 and employee
以404和员工的身份向用户展示
not found so just to emphasize their
找不到所以只是为了强调他们
errors or not they are just values the
错误或不只是它们的价值
same as anything else and you need to
与其他任何东西一样，您需要
pass them on as you would a string or an
像将字符串或字符串那样传递给它们
employee or or whatever it might be the
员工或其他
next one we can look at is find problem
我们可以看的下一个是发现问题
records and again we're going to make
记录，我们将再次制作
we're going to avoid the first mistake
我们将避免第一个错误
that I made earlier so we want to return
我之前做的，所以我们想回来
a flux of employee and obviously that
员工流动，显然
causes a problem because that's not what
引起问题，因为那不是
we're doing anymore so we need a flux
我们正在做，所以我们需要一个通量
and we already know of a method that
而且我们已经知道一种方法
will generate a flux for us
会为我们带来通量
and then we want to do something with
然后我们想做些事情
this list that will get rid of all the
这个清单将摆脱所有
employees who are fine you are good and
优秀的员工你就是好人
we'll just leave the ones that have
我们将只留下那些
problems with them now in the imperative
现在必须解决他们的问题
code that I was using earlier you can
我之前使用的代码可以
see that I'd created a couple of lists
看到我创建了几个列表
one of the result I initially got back
我最初回来的结果之一
from my repository and then a second one
从我的存储库中，然后是第二个
where I could put all the users that
我可以把所有用户
were problematic to pass back there are
回传有问题
various ways of doing that the reason
各种方式做到这一点的原因
I've chosen this was because other some
我选择这是因为其他一些
of the other ways of doing it can cause
其他方式可能导致
concurrency problems that if you're
并发问题
trying to update a list that you're also
尝试更新您也是的列表
reading from then it things can start
从那时开始，事情就可以开始了
strip over so we want a way that is not
剥离，所以我们想要一种不
going to cause that sort of problem
会引起那种问题
using a reactive flow and ultimately
使用反应流，最终
what we want to do is to filter the
我们要做的是过滤
results that we get from this initial
我们从这个初始得到的结果
flux so that we can discard anything
通量，以便我们可以丢弃任何东西
that doesn't meet our criteria of having
不符合我们的标准
a problem with it and handily there is a
有一个问题，很方便
filter so that filter takes I can't
筛选器，以便筛选器无法
spell an employee and we'll do something
给员工打拼，我们会做些事情
with it to perform a test on it and it
用它来对其进行测试
checks to see whether that employee has
检查该员工是否有
some problems important thing to note
一些问题要注意的重要事项
here is that once we get into the filter
这是一旦我们进入过滤器
and we have this employee this took me a
我们有这个员工，这让我
while to fully wrap my head around I've
同时把我的头完全缠住
made that singular for a reason although
尽管有一个原因使之单数
we have a flux of all of the employees
我们所有员工都有变动
once it gets inside the filter then it's
一旦进入过滤器，那就是
just dealing with a single employee and
只是与一个员工打交道，
we'll have if you imagine as many filter
如果您能想象有那么多的过滤器，我们将有
instances it's not really an instance
实例不是真正的实例
but that's the idea
但这就是想法
working on this flux each dealing with a
处理此通量，每个处理一个
particular employee as it needs to
需要的特定员工
process all of the data and what happens
处理所有数据以及会发生什么
is that each of those filter instances
是每个过滤器实例
we'll drop one of the employees if it
如果有的话，我们会丢掉一名员工
says yeah that's fine it passes my test
说是的，这很好，它通过了我的测试
the the or it we don't have a problem
该或它我们没有问题
with this particular user so what's left
与这个特定的用户，还剩下什么
behind after we've done that is just a
完成之后，这只是一个
flux that contains the users that do
包含用户的流量
have a problem we've discarded all the
有一个问题，我们已经丢弃了所有
others which means that this code is now
其他，这意味着该代码现在
complete it's actually surprised me when
完成，实际上让我感到惊讶
I first did this I thought I would have
我首先这样做，我以为我会
to have another line but we've got rid
有另一条线，但我们已经摆脱了
of everything that doesn't meet the
所有不符合的
criteria we want so what we're left with
我们想要的标准，所以我们剩下的是
is a problem employees and that's still
是员工的问题，现在仍然
a flux because we've just filtered the
通量，因为我们刚刚过滤了
flux we haven't changed it in some way
通量，我们没有以某种方式改变它
it gets passed on to web flux and again
它被传递到网络流量，并再次
it presents it to whoever's calling it
呈现给任何人
one little thing that will probably be
一件事可能是
upsetting some of you IntelliJ PRS
使某些人感到沮丧
because I'm passing an employee to a
因为我要把员工传给
method that only requires an employee we
只需要一名员工的方法
can do a simplification of the code like
可以简化代码，例如
that
那
okay so the next thing we can do is a
好的，接下来我们可以做的是
new employee this one's a little
新员工，这有点
trickier because we're making this call
比较棘手，因为我们正在打电话
out the first thing we might think of
我们可能想到的第一件事
doing is saying well I need a name
就是说我需要一个名字
that's fine I've got a name and I need
很好，我有个名字，我需要
the pension ID for that employee
该雇员的退休金编号
okay well I'll do new employee don't let
好吧，我会做新员工的
me try this again
我再试一次
I need the pension ID and I can do a
我需要退休金ID，我可以做一个
pension look upon it with that name and
退休金用这个名字看
then well I need that value so how do I
那么我需要那个价值，那我该怎么办
get that value and this is where it
得到那个价值，这就是它的所在
kinda starts to go wrong because I'm not
有点开始出错，因为我不是
programming in a reactive style I've
我已经以反应式编程
started in in an imperative style and
从命令式开始
what I actually want to do is start
我真正想做的就是开始
somewhere with either a mono or a flux
具有单声道或通量的地方
to say this is the flow that we are
说这就是我们的流程
doing so what I want is something here
这样做我想要的是这里的东西
that will provide me with a mono I could
那会给我一个单声道
just create one with a mono just as
就像用一个单声道创建一个一样
we've seen already but actually there's
我们已经看过了，但实际上
going to be some code here that will
这里将是一些代码
provide me with a mono if I start making
如果我开始制作，请给我一个单声道
some changes but the moment we're using
有些变化，但是我们正在使用的那一刻
a rest template which is perfectly fine
一个休息模板，非常好
reasonable web MVC choice but as we saw
合理的Web MVC选择，但正如我们所见
in the keynote actually it is a blocking
在主题演讲中实际上是一个障碍
call which means that we act on a single
通话，这意味着我们要对一个人采取行动
thread it's not really reactive so we
线程不是真正的反应性，所以我们
need to change that and the way we
需要改变这一点以及我们的方式
change that is we will have the web
改变就是我们将拥有网络
client that was mentioned earlier and we
前面提到的客户，我们
would like wouldn't it be great if
想如果不是很好
spring boot could provide us with one of
spring boot 可以为我们提供
those
那些
come on spell
加咒
and then we want to webclient is that
然后我们要webclient是
except coding standing up is a very
除了编码站起来是一个非常
weird art builder okay so we've got a
怪异的艺术建造者好吧，所以我们有一个
basic one there's all sorts of
基本的有各种各样的
configuration that we can do on it we
我们可以对其进行配置
want to base URL and I know that that is
想要基于URL，我知道那是
localhost 8080 too so that's all I need
本地主机8080也是我所需要的
to create my web client spring boot in
在创建我的Web客户端 spring boot
the background is doing all the magic
背景正在发挥所有魔力
for me to give it sensible options if I
如果我愿意给我明智的选择
go down to my pension lock up clearly
归结到我的养老金锁得很清楚
this is now out of date because it's
现在已经过时了，因为
using the rest template so instead I
使用其余的模板，所以我
need the web client I'm going to do get
需要我要做的网络客户端
the URI I'm going to call so that's an
我要呼叫的URI，
extension to the base URL is name I'm
基本URL的扩展名是我的名字
going to parameterize that then I'm
要参数化然后我
going to retrieve the result and I
要检索结果，我
happen to know that the result that
碰巧知道结果
comes back is just a string it's nothing
回来只是一个字符串而已
fancy so I'm going to body tamao and
看中了，所以我要去身体tamaño，
it's a strained
这很紧张
and again we've got the error because
再一次，我们得到了错误，因为
I'm saying that this is providing a
我是说这提供了一个
string and no longer in our proof
字符串，不再在我们的证明中
it now provides a mono / string and
现在，它提供了单声道/字符串和
again go programming put in that
再次去编程
semicolon so now we've got the
分号，所以现在我们有了
infrastructure set up we can go back to
基础设施设置我们可以回到
our code here and think I've just
我们的代码在这里，以为我只是
created something that will provide a
创建了一些可以提供
mono for me so why don't I start with
单声道对我来说，为什么我不开始
that pension lockup just going to return
退休金锁定只是要回来
a mono I can get the name that's easy
一个单声道，我可以得到一个简单的名字
enough it's in the new employee and then
足够在新员工中，然后
I want to do something with that and the
我想为此做些什么
way we very often will do something with
我们经常会做的事情
that is to use flatmap which says I'm
那就是使用平面图，说我
effectively I'm going to do reactive
有效地，我将要做反应式
work on this piece of data that you're
处理您正在处理的这些数据
passing in in mono it's a little odd
以单声道传递它有点奇怪
because one of the implications of
因为其中的含义之一
flatmap is I'm going to create a number
平面图是我要创建一个数字
of processes that will deal with one
的过程将处理一个
each of the items that you're passing in
您传递的每个项目
to me or a mono we know that's going to
对我或单声道来说，我们知道
be a single one nonetheless that's the
还是一个人
same pattern that we want to use across
我们想要跨使用的相同模式
both of them so I'm going to get the
他们两个，所以我要去
pension ID from that incidentally
附带的养老金ID
something that took me a while to work
我花了一些时间去工作的东西
out I would call that pension ID you can
出来，我会打电话给你的退休金ID
call it P if you want it's not a
如果您不希望它叫做P
particular value it's just a name that
特殊的价值，只是一个名字
you're assigning if you've been using
您正在分配是否一直在使用
Java rate streams for example then you
例如，Java速率流
should be very familiar with that idea
应该对这个想法很熟悉
so I want to do something with this
所以我想做点什么
pension ID I want to make sure I get it
养老金ID，我想确保得到它
right as well
也是对的
okay I want to do two things I've got
好吧，我想做两件事
the new employee I want to set this
我要设置的新员工
pension ID to be that pension ID and now
退休金ID是该退休金ID，现在
an important thing I want to return
我想回来的一件重要的事情
something that my flow can continue with
我的流可以继续的东西
and in this case that's fairly
在这种情况下，
straightforward I can use the new
简单的我可以使用新的
employee that I've got and finally I
我拥有的员工，最后我
need to do something with that employee
需要和那个员工做些事情
and I want to save to the repository in
我想保存到
fact I can do that more easily
实际上我可以更轻松地做到这一点
and again I want to return a mono F
再一次我想返回单声道F
employee oh dear
员工哦亲爱的
that's the wrong isn't it there we go
那是错误的，不是吗？
yeah as I said normal developer make
是的，正如我所说的，普通开发商
normal mistakes
正常错误
so that bit of code now should be okay
所以现在的代码应该可以了
we've got a flat map there which says I
我们那里有一张平面图，上面写着
will take each individual item that you
会拿走您的每一项
send me being just one in this case but
在这种情况下让我成为一个
it could be many and I will do whatever
可能很多，我会做任何事情
process you tell me to do on it and then
你告诉我要做的过程，然后
at the end we have a map which is
最后我们有一张地图
essentially a synchronous call for
本质上是同步调用
trivial behavior if you like that just
琐碎的行为，如果你只是喜欢
says save it to the repository we're
说将其保存到我们的存储库中
done so we have a very similar method
完成，所以我们有一个非常相似的方法
that we want to call but instead of just
我们想打电话给我们，而不只是
doing one pension update one call to the
进行一项养老金更新会致电一位
pension service we're going to do
我们要做的养老金服务
multiple calls so we need to do a
多次通话，所以我们需要做一个
similar conversion on that and if we
类似的转换，如果我们
first change that so I get it right were
首先更改，使我正确
you all feeling sep 10 that I put in the
你们都觉得我把9月10日放进去
wrong place I could feel a certain
我可以感觉到一定的错误的地方
concern so again we know how to create a
再次关注，我们知道如何创建一个
flux that will have some information
会有一些信息的助焊剂
that's interesting to us you can start
对我们来说很有趣，您可以开始
with find all and then as we've just
找到全部，然后就像我们刚刚
seen we're going to do a flat map again
看到我们要再次做平面图
because we want to do something with the
因为我们想对
values that come out of that that
由此产生的价值
iterable that we've turned into a flux
我们变成了不断变化的
this time it's a little more interesting
这次更有趣了
because we're actually going to get
因为我们实际上会得到
multiple values out of it so if we take
其中有多个值，如果我们采取
or we're going to get an employee out of
否则我们将使一名雇员离开
that and we're going to want to do
那，我们将要做
something with that employee
那位员工的事
[Music]
[音乐]
again I want to make sure that I get
再次，我想确保我得到
this one what right so let's do that we
这是正确的，所以让我们做到这一点
into your pension lockup on it and we
进入您的养老金锁定，我们
need the name so that it can do the
需要名称，以便它可以
pension lookup and then we want to take
养老金查询，然后我们要
the result of that and do a flat map
结果，然后做一个平面图
this time it's a mono because we're just
这次是单声道，因为我们只是
going to get one value back but it's
将获得一个价值，但它是
buried inside this flat map we've got
埋在这张平面图中
going on so we'll get a pension ID come
继续，所以我们会拿到退休金ID
back from that
从那回来
I'm much like the code that we just
我很喜欢我们刚才的代码
wrote we don't want to do two things for
写我们不想做两件事
that we want to update the pension ID
我们要更新退休金ID
with that value and again we want to
有了这个价值，我们再次想
return an employee so that the next step
返回一名员工，以便下一步
has something to work on and again the
有一些工作要做，然后再次
final step that we want to do is to
我们要做的最后一步是
actually save it
实际保存
and I need another
我需要另一个
thing there somewhere
那里的东西
sixteen sixty sixty six thank you
十六六十六六谢谢
do you have returns Ingo I can't
你有退货吗？
remember okay so this is the more
记住好吧，这是更多
interesting one because I still need my
有趣的一个，因为我仍然需要我的
know this is a more interesting one
知道这是一个更有趣的
because we're using flatmap more for the
因为我们将平面图更多地用于
for the impressive purpose that it has
为了它令人印象深刻的目的
that we start off we've got employee and
从一开始我们就有员工
we're going to take each one of those
我们将采取其中每一个
individual employees and we're going to
个人员工，我们将
do the pension look up pension look up
养老金查询吗养老金查询吗
for update the record and save to the
用于更新记录并保存到
repository so if we've got a hundred
如果我们有一百个
employees that we need to check the
我们需要检查的员工
details on an update then it will
更新的详细信息，然后它将
potentially spin up one hundred
可能旋转一百
processes that we'll be able to do those
我们能够做到的流程
in parallel or as close to parallel as
平行或接近平行
it decides is appropriate a lot of the
它决定适当的很多
work that's gone into reactor is making
反应堆正在做的工作
sure that it has good defaults for
确保它具有良好的默认值
things like the number of threads I
线程数之类的东西
think it was mentioned earlier that it's
认为之前提到过
typically the number of physical CPUs on
通常情况下，物理CPU的数量
your machine so all of that is something
您的机器，所有这些都是
that you can tweak but you should
你可以调整，但你应该
probably think about that and first get
大概考虑一下，首先
used to the programming method in
习惯于
general so if I try and run that now
一般，如果我现在尝试运行
then with a little luck we did our
然后幸运的是我们做了
Creator user I should probably restart
创建者用户我应该重新启动
as well that will help
也会有帮助
no obvious alias I must have the right
没有明显的别名，我必须拥有正确的权限
number of semicolons in there so when I
分号的数量，所以当我
do my call again it works famously did
再次打电话给我，它很有名
before I looked up the pension ID if I
在我查询退休金编号之前，如果我
do my clean so I make multiple calls out
做我的清洁，所以我打了多个电话
to the pension provider you may notice
您可能会注意到养老金提供者
that that was quicker and that's because
那是更快，那是因为
if we look over on the contour I forgot
如果我们看过我忘记的轮廓
to put in the thing didn't I I'll just
放东西不是，我只是
steal this piece of code
窃取这段代码
you know
你懂
stone that's again
石头又是
so I make that call and if I look down
所以我打了电话，如果我往下看
in my console and the size that you can
在我的控制台中，您可以
see you can see without me having to
看到你可以看到而无需我
think about coordinating different
考虑协调不同
things that are going on reactor has
反应堆正在发生的事情
taken care of the threading for me it's
照顾我的线程是
used for threads because this is a fork
用于线程，因为这是一个分支
or machine or for CPU machine I guess
我猜是机器还是CPU机器
and has made the process faster without
并加快了流程，而无需
me having to think about anything and it
我不得不考虑任何事情
just happened by magic or almost by
只是因为魔术或几乎是偶然发生的
magic ok so let's have a quick summary
魔术好吧，让我们快速总结一下
of what we've been doing there we've had
我们在那里所做的一切
a quick look at what flux and mono are
快速了解一下通量和单声道是什么
the important thing being flux is a zero
重要的是通量是零
too many Manos to zero to one it's a
太多的Manos零到一，这是一个
different way of thinking about it
不同的思考方式
limitless than the options that you've
无限多于您拥有的选择
got helps you to think about processing
得到帮助您考虑处理
individual items we looked a little bit
个别物品，我们看起来有点
at map which is doing that that
在这样做的地图上
synchronous call and the flat map which
同步呼叫和平面图
is part of the real cleverness of
是真正聪明的一部分
project reactor of sharing out this
分享这个的项目反应堆
workload and then bringing it all back
工作量，然后将其全部带回
together so that you just get a single
在一起，所以你只得到一个
flux at the end of it that will think
最后的通量会认为
and then be processed errors are just
然后被处理的错误只是
values I stress that at the time so we
我当时强调的价值观
want to be able to be resilient and we
希望能够有韧性，我们
can do that if we're passing around
如果我们过去的话可以做到这一点
errors rather than just exploding as
错误而不仅仅是爆炸
soon as we hit upon something a key
当我们碰到钥匙的时候
thing that needs to be emphasized this
需要强调的事情
you should stay reactive so we start
你应该保持被动，所以我们开始
each flow by coming up with some sort of
通过提出某种
flux or mono and then we try and stay in
通量或单声道，然后我们尝试停留在
that pan one of the most common mistakes
这是最常见的错误之一
that people make is there is a method on
人们做的有一种方法
a flux or a mono called dot block which
通量或称为点块的单声道
lets you retrieve the value at that time
让您在那时检索值
and particularly few start to get into
特别是很少进入
more complicated flows that what the
更复杂的流程
stuff we've seen here is quite simple
我们在这里看到的东西很简单
you get halfway through and you think I
你走到一半，你以为我
just need that employee name if I can
如果可以的话，只需要那个雇员的名字
get that then I can do the rest of this
知道了，那么我可以做剩下的事情
and you put in a dot block back in the
然后将一个点块放回
day when I started with it it was called
我开始的那一天被称为
get which was far too tempting now block
得到太诱人了现在阻止
we're starting to realize block is a bad
我们开始意识到阻止是一个坏习惯
thing so you try and avoid that command
事情，所以您尝试避免该命令
and there will be a way to follow
并且会有一种方法可以遵循
through the logic of stay
通过停留的逻辑
reactive and making your entire flow
反应性，使您的整个流程
reactive one thing we didn't get to too
反应性一件事我们也没有去
much is it doesn't replace what you know
这是多少并不能取代你所知道的
you can still use Java rate streams and
您仍然可以使用Java速率流和
if you want to call a method that does
如果你想调用一个方法
some processing as long as that method
只要该方法就可以进行一些处理
returns a mono or a flux depending on
返回单声道或通量，具体取决于
what you're doing you can have
你在做什么，你可以拥有
if-then-else inside there you can do the
如果，然后在里面，你可以做其他
streams to manipulate strings or
流来操纵字符串或
whatever you might be doing so this
不管你怎么做，这
builds on what you know it can be really
建立在您真正知道的基础上
intimidating at first one of my
吓到我的第一个
colleagues described it as when you're
同事形容为您
learning Java there's quite a shallow
学习Java相当浅
learning curve and then to get really
学习曲线然后真正地
good at it it gets really steep as you
擅长它，随着你变得非常陡峭
getting into all the complex options
进入所有复杂的选择
that Java provides reactors kind of the
Java提供的反应堆
opposite that it starts off really
相反，它真的开始了
complicated because it's a whole new way
复杂，因为这是一种全新的方式
of thinking about how to create quo but
关于如何创建现状的​​思考，
the relatively few commands available to
可用的相对较少的命令
you I think there's between flux and
你我认为介于通量和
miles maybe 200 something like that most
英里大概是200英里
many of them shared so it's actually
他们中很多人都分享了，所以实际上
possible to get a grasp of pretty much
可能几乎掌握
everything that reactor offers some
反应堆提供的一切
resources for you there's the reactor
为您准备的资源有反应堆
manifesto and the reactive streams or
宣言和反应流或
that we mentioned earlier project
我们之前提到的项目
reactors home itself really good
反应堆家本身真的很好
documentation on there not just the
那里的文件不只是
Javadoc and stuff like that but it
Javadoc之类的东西，但是它
really takes you through here's what the
真的带您通过这里
flux actually is here's what we mean
通量实际上就是我们的意思
when we flatmap what we're doing
当我们绘制平面图时，我们在做什么
underneath the covers something that I
在掩护下，我
particularly like inside there is the
特别像里面有
choosing an operator page where you can
选择一个可以在其中操作的页面
sit there and say okay well what I want
坐在那里，好吧，我想要什么
to do is to filter the output that I'm
要做的是过滤我的输出
getting here and say all right well you
到这里说好吧你
need to use a filter then it's really
需要使用过滤器，那么它真的
useful when you're first starting out
当您第一次开始时很有用
and you just don't know what any of
而你只是不知道
these things might mean reference to the
这些事情可能意味着参考
spring web reactive the code for this
Spring Web对此的代码
presentation will be at that URL that's
演示文稿将位于该URL
not there yet but I'll get there and the
还没到，但我会到那里，
final thing I wanted to mention as I
我想提的最后一件事
said at the start I started out with
说一开始我是从
reactive on the CF Java client and
在CF Java客户端上反应
because it grew up with project reactor
因为它随着项目反应堆一起成长
it is an excellent resource I'm not
这是一个很好的资源，我不是
boasting there were many more people
吹牛还有更多的人
than me involved in it
比我参与其中
excellent resource of examples of how
优秀的例子资源
you actually do reactive when you've got
你实际上有反应时
complicated code when you've got the
当你有复杂的代码
sort of branching that I didn't even
我什至没有的那种分支
dare to get into today wander through
敢进入今天徘徊
there particularly if you have a look
那里特别是如果你看看
through the the integration tests which
通过集成测试
are pretty extensive you'll get an idea
相当广泛，您将会有个主意
of what you can achieve in inside
在内部可以实现的目标
project reactor so the clock down here I
项目反应堆，所以这里的时钟我
think has been corrected and now tells
认为已经纠正，现在可以告诉
me that I have 10 seconds left
我还有十秒钟
so all that remains is for me to thank
所以剩下的就是我要感谢的
you so very very many of you for being
你们中的很多人
here for my first ever live coding
这是我第一次现场编码
session I'm going to be hanging around
会议我要闲逛
the back if you need me and this one two
后面，如果你需要我，这两个
of my colleagues who will also be able
我的同事们也将能够
to help out with any questions you have
帮助您解决任何问题
thanks very much
非常感谢
[Applause]
[掌声]
[Music]
[音乐]